Register of the Poland. Poselstwo (Czechoslovakia) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Poselstwo (Czechoslovakia) records,
1941-1945
59028
Poland. Poselstwo (Czechoslovakia)
16 manuscript boxes (6.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, dispatches, memoranda, bulletins, and printed matter, relating to Polish-Czechoslovak relations, conditions in Poland and Czechoslovakia during World War II, and Allied diplomacy during the war. A digital copy of this entire collection is available at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/44/0/-/.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (17 reels).
Digital copy in Poland's National Digital Archive at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/44/0/-/. It was digitized from microfilm by the Polish State Archives.
Historical Note
Polish legation with the Czechoslovak government-in-exile in London during World War II.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Polish legation to the Czechoslovak government in London are the only extant ones of this diplomatic post, and document the wartime relationship of those two governments. The bulk of the material dates from 1941 to 1945 and is almost entirely devoted to the idea of creating a confederation between Poland and Czechoslovakia.
Poland had suspended diplomatic relations with Czechoslovakia after the latter's annexation by Germany in March 1939, but re-established contact the following year on French soil, where leaders of both countries had regrouped after the outbreak of the war. With the fall of France in June 1940, they set up governments-in-exile in London and renewed regular diplomatic relations with each other. The rapprochement between the two countries was facilitated by the fact that Wladyslaw Sikorski, long before he became prime minister in 1939, had warned Poland's ruling elites against isolationism.
The plan for a confederation was born of wartime exigency and constituted a bold step for two countries that had no history of close ties between them. In 1940, both wished to prevent, once and for all, their history of occupation and division from repeating itself. They sought not only to strengthen their security but also to create friendly relations as a guarantee of a new post-war order. One must also note that Poland, although hoping for stronger ties with other central and eastern European countries as well, considered Czechoslovakia the most important strategic partner, given that its level of industrial development was extremely high.
General Sikorski strongly supported the idea for a confederation. In addition, there were many other planers in this project who staffed committees and wrote papers, most of whom remain anonymous. Following the war, the communist regimes in Warsaw and Prague blocked the direct evolution of the confederation idea as planned in these records, but those experts involved from the beginning continued to be active well into the 1950s among the circles shaping the idea of a united Western Europe.
Other important topics in addition to the Polish-Czechoslovak confederation include the Munich Agreement, Poland's borders, Teschen Silesia, relations with the Balkan states and with the Soviet Union, the steel industry, the persecution of Jews in occupied Poland, and wartime intelligence. There are also files relating to such public figures as General Sikorski, Eduard Benes, Jan Masaryk, Stefan Osusky, Hubert Ripka.
These records were formerly part of the Poland's Foreign Ministry collection, acquired by the Hoover Archives in 1959, and were accessioned in the early 1990s as a separate collection. The legation, however, used its own classification system (given here, in a series list, both in English and Polish), different from the one used by all other Polish diplomatic posts. (For a complete listing of the index numbers in that classification system, please consult the series list of the register to the "Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych" records.)
A microfilm copy of these materials has been deposited in the State Archives of Poland in Warsaw.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Czechoslovakia--Foreign relations--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Czechoslovakia.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.; Czechoslovakia--History--1938-1945.; World War, 1939-1945.; Poland.; Czechoslovakia.; Poland--Foreign relations--Czechoslovakia.
Series List in English
Series Numbers and Titles
- 0. Log Books (Box 1)
- I. General - Political Issues (Box 1)
  - A/Reports
  - B/Talks
  - C/Political institutions
  - D/Notes
- II. Key Documents on Polish-Czechoslovak Cooperation (Box 2)
  - A/Polish-Czechoslovak declaration
  - B/Correspondence between General Sikorski and President Benes
  - C/Miscellany. Correspondence and notes
- III. Polish-Czechoslovak Founding Act (Box 2)
  - A/New editions
  - B/Protocols
  - C/Evaluations
  - D/Various supplementary materials
- IV. Mixed Polish-Czechoslovak Committees (Box 3-4)
  - A/Coordination Committee
  - B/Foreign Affairs Committee
  - C/Information Committee
  - D/Cultural Cooperation Committee
  - E/Political-Legal Committee
  - F/Social Policy Committee
  - G/
  - H/Military Committee
- V. Polish-Czechoslovak Cooperation (Box 4)
- VI. Czechoslovakia. Government and Administration (Box 5-8)
  - A/President
  - B/Government (legal status, members, etc.)
  - C/State Council
  - D/Foreign representations and diplomatic corps
  - E/Occupied Czechoslovakia
  - F/Organizations, opposition groups
  - G/Biographies
- VII. Poland. Government and Administration (Box 8-9)
  - A/President
  - B/Government
  - C/State Council
  - D/Diplomatic corps
  - E/Occupied Poland
  - F/Polish organizations abroad
  - G/Polish borders
- VIII. Political Conditions (Box 9-10)
  - A/Reports
  - B/Political guidelines
  - C/Inter-governmental committees, international conditions
  - D/Exchange of political intelligence data
  - E/Other
  - F/International organizations, League of Nations
- IX. Economic Issues (Box 10)
  - A/Poland
  - B/Czechoslovakia
  - C/General reports
  - D/Slask Cieszynski (Teschen Silesia)
- X. Administrative Operations (Box 10-11)
  - A/Addresses and financial matters
  - B/Diplomatic protocol
  - C/Medals and awards (mail and rent)
  - D/Personnel files (state employees)
  - E/Budget
  - F/Library and publications
  - G/Office issues
- XI. Varia (Box 11)
  - A/Mailing procedures
  - B/Treatment of correspondence
  - C/Meetings, congresses, social organizations, courses
- XII. Consular Matters (Box 12)
  - A/Interventions
  - B/Legal issues
  - C/Circulars
  - D/Archives
- XIII. Press and Publications (Box 12-14)
  - A/Polish
    - a/Press interviews
    - b/Polish press on Czechoslovakia
    - c/Propaganda publications
  - B/Czechoslovak
    - a/Press reports
    - b/Czechoslovak press on Poland
    - c/Publications
    - d/Uredni Vestnik Ceskoslovensky
  - C/Other
    - a/British press on Czechoslovakia
    - b/German press on Czechoslovakia
    - c/Publications on federation
    - d/Soviet press on Czechoslovakia
    - e/Non-involved countries on Poland and Czechoslovakia
    - f/British publications
- XIV. Special Dossiers (Box 14-16)
  - A/Slovakia
  - B/Poland's borders
  - C/Main acts on Polish-Czechoslovak cooperation
  - D/Balkan states and Danube Basin
  - E/Slask Cieszynski (Teschen Silesia)
  - F/Soviet-Czechoslovak relations
  - G/Rus Podkarpacka (Subcarpathian Ukraine)
Series List in Polish
Series Numbers and Titles
- 0. DZIENNIK PODAWCZY (Box 1)
- I. OGOLNO-POLITYCZNA (Box 1)
  - A/Raporty
  - B/Rozmowy
  - C/Instytucje polityczne
  - D/Noty
- II. ZASADNICZE DOKUMENTY DOTYCZACE WSPOLPRACY POLSKO-CZECHOSLOWACKIEJ (Box 2)
  - A/Deklaracja polsko-czechoslowacka
  - B/Koresponencje Generala Sikorskiego z Prezydentem Benesem
  - C/Inne
- III. PROJEKTY AKTU KONSTYTUCYJNEGO POLSKO-CZECHOSLOWACKIEGO (Box 2)
  - A/Kolejne projekty aktu konstytucyjnego
  - B/Protokoly
  - C/Opinie w sprawie aktu konstytucyjnego
  - D/Rozne materialy do aktu konstytucyjnego
- IV. KOMITETY MIESZANE POLSKO-CZECHOSLOWACKIE (Box 3-4)
  - A/Komitet Koordynacyjny
  - B/Komitet Spraw Zagranicznych
  - C/Komitet Informacji
  - D/Komitet Wspolpracy Kulturalnej
  - E/Komitet Polityczno-Prawny
  - F/Komitet Gospodarczo Finansowy
  - G/Komitet Polityki Spolecznej
  - H/Komitet Wojskowy
- V. WPOLPRACA POLSKO-CZECHOSLOWACKA (Box 4)
  - A/Uwagi placowek i urzedow
  - B/
  - C/Organizacje i instytutcje wspolpracy poza komitetami
  - D/Sprawozdania o wspolpracy
  - E/Rozne
  - F/Inicjatywy postronne
  - G/Granice Polski z Czechoslowacja
- VI. CZECHOSLOWACJA. RZAD I WLADZE (Box 5-8)
  - A/Prezydent
    - 1/Personalia
    - 2/Rozmowy
    - 3/Mowy, deklaracje
  - B/Rzad (stanowisko prawne, sklad, etc.)
  - C/Rada Panstwowa
  - D/Placowki zagraniczne i korpus dyplomatyczny
  - E/Kraj okupowany
  - F/Organizacje, opozycja
  - G/Zyciorysy, od 1943 zamieniono na Slowacje
- VII. POLSKA. RZAD I WLADZE (Box 8-9)
  - A/Prezydent
  - B/Rzad
  - C/Rada Narodowa
  - D/Korpus dyplomatyczny
  - E/Kraj okupowany
  - F/Organizacje
  - G/Granice Polski
- VIII. OGOLNA SYTUACJA POLITYCZNA (Box 9-10)
  - A/Sprawozdania
  - B/Instrukcje polityczne (przeniesione do t. I)
  - C/Komitety miedzysojusznicze, nastroje miedzynarodowe
  - D/Wymiana informacji politycznych
  - E/Rozne
  - F/Organizacje miedzynarodowe, Liga Narodow
- IX. ZAGADNIENIA GOSPODARCZE (Box 10)
  - A/Polska
  - B/Czechoslowacja
  - C/Raporty ogolne
  - D/Slask Cieszynski
- X. ADMINISTRACJA (Box 10-11)
  - A/Adresy
  - B/Protokol
  - C/Odznanczenia i ordery
  - D/Personalne (urzednicy)
  - E/Budzet
  - F/Biblioteka
  - G/Kancelaryjne
- XI. ROZNE (Box 11)
  - A/Przesylanie korespondencji
  - B/Inna korespondencja
  - C/Zebrania, kongresy, organiacje spoleczne, kursy
- XII. SPRAWY KONSULARNE (Box 12)
  - A/Interwencje
  - B/Ogolno-prawne
  - C/Okolniki
  - D/Archiwum
- XIII. PRASA I WYDAWNICTWA (Box 12-14)
  - A/Polskie
    - a/Wywiady prasowe
    - b/Prasa polska o Czechoslowacji
    - c/Wydawnictwa I publikacje
  - B/Czechoslowackie
    - a/Sprawozdania prasowe
    - b/Prasa Czechoslowacka o Polsce
    - c/Wydawnictwa i publikacje
    - d/Uredni Vestnik Ceskoslovensky
  - C/Inne
    - a/Prasa angielska o Czechoslowacji
    - b/Prasa niemiecka o Czechoslowacji
    - c/Prasa I wydawnictwa o federalizmie
    - d/Prasa sowiecka o Czechoslowacji
    - e/Neutralna o Polsce I czechoslowacji
    - f/Wydawnictwa angielskie
- XIV. TECZKI SPECJALNE (Box 14-16)
  - A/Slowacja
  - B/Granice Polski
  - C/Zasadnicze akty wspolpracy Polsko-Czechoslowackiej
  - D/Kraje balkanskie i basenu dunajskiego
  - E/Materialy dotyczace Slaska Cieszynskiego
  - F/Stosunki sowiecko-czechoslowackie
  - G/Rus Podkarpacka
Container List
- SERIES NO. 0. LOG BOOKS (Box 1)
  - 1940-1941 (Folder 1: 1)
  - 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 2)
  - 1944 (Folder 1: 3)
- SERIES NO. I. GENERAL. POLITICAL ISSUES
  - A/Reports
    - 1941 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1942 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1943 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1944
      - General (Folder 1: 7)
      - Germany's post-war economy (Folder 1: 8)
      - Poland's eastern provinces (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1945 (Folder 1: 10)
  - B/Talks
    - 1941 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1942 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1943 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1944 (Folder 1: 14)
  - D/Notes. 1944 (Folder 1: 15)
- SERIES NO. II. KEY DOCUMENTS ON POLISH-CZECHOSLOVAK COOPERATION (Box 2)
  - A/Correspondence between General Sikorski and President Benes
    - 1940 (Folder 2: 1)
    - 1941 (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1942 (Folder 2: 3)
  - C/Miscellany.
    Correspondence and notes
    - 1942 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1943
      - January-May (Folder 2: 5)
      - June-October (Folder 2: 6)
- SERIES NO. III. POLISH-CZECHOSLOVAK FOUNDING ACT
  - A/New editions - 1941-1942 (Folder 2: 7)
  - B/Protocols
    - 1940 (Folder 2: 8)
    - 1941 (Folder 2: 9)
    - 1942 (Folder 2: 10)
  - C/Evaluations
    - 1940 (Folder 2: 11)
    - 1941 (Folder 2: 12)
  - D/Various supplementary materials
    - 1940 (Folder 2: 13)
    - 1941 (Folder 2: 14)
- SERIES NO. IV. MIXED POLISH-CZECHOSLOVAK COMMITTEES (Box 3)
  - A/Coordination Committee
    - 1941
      - General
        - General (Folder 3: 1)
        - January-March (Folder 3: 2)
        - April-June (Folder 3: 3)
        - September-November (Folder 3: 4)
      - List of members (Folder 3: 5)
    - 1942 (Folder 3: 6)
  - B/Foreign Affairs Committee, 1941 - Sessions
    - First (Folder 3: 7)
    - Second (Folder 3: 8)
    - Third (Folder 3: 9)
    - Fourth (Folder 3: 10)
    - Fifth (Folder 3: 11)
  - C/Information Committee, 1941 (Folder 3: 12)
  - D/Cultural Cooperation Committee
    - 1941
      - General (Folder 3: 13)
      - Minutes (Folder 3: 14)
    - 1942 (Folder 3: 15)
    - 1943 (Folder 3: 16)
  - E/Political-Legal Committee, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - F/Social Policy Committee
    - 1941 (Folder 4: 2)
    - 1942 (Folder 4: 3)
  - H/Military Committee, 1941. (Folder 4: 4)
    Includes materials on Polish-Czechoslovak-German border
- SERIES NO. V. POLISH-CZECHOSOLOVAK COOPERATION
  - A/Comments from diplomatic representations and government offices
    - 1941 (Folder 4: 5)
    - 1942 (Folder 4: 6)
    - 1943 (Folder 4: 7)
  - C/Non-committee organizations and institutions
    - 1941 (Folder 4: 8)
    - 1942 (Folder 4: 9)
    - 1943 (Folder 4: 10)
  - D/Reports
    - 1941
      - Cooperation in steel industry (Folder 4: 11)
      - Diplomatic representations (Folder 4: 12)
    - 1942 (Folder 4: 13)
  - E/Miscellany
    - 1941 (Folder 4: 14)
    - 1943 (Folder 4: 15)
  - F/Other non-government initiatives
    - 1941 (Folder 4: 16)
    - 1942. (Folder 4: 17)
      Includes documents on Czech cadets in merchant fleet
    - 1943 (Folder 4: 18)
  - G/Polish-Czechoslovak border, 1941 - Slask Cieszynski
    - General (Folder 4: 19)
    - Maps (Folder 4: 20)
- SERIES NO. VI. CZECHOSLOVAKIA. GOVERNMENT AND ADMINISTRATION (Box 5)
  - A/President
    - 1941
      - General (Folder 5: 1)
      - Speeches (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1942
      - General (Folder 5: 3)
      - Speeches (Folder 5: 4)
    - 1943
      - General
        - General (Folder 5: 5)
        - Speeches (Folder 5: 6)
      - Trips
        - Moscow (Folder 5: 7)
        - United States
          - General (Folder 5: 8)
          - Speeches (Folder 5: 9)
    - 1944
      - General (Folder 5: 10)
      - Speeches (Folder 5: 11)
    - 1945 (Folder 5: 12)
  - B/Government
    - 1941
      - General (Folder 5: 13)
      - Legal status (Folder 5: 14)
      - Masaryk, Jan (Folder 5: 15)
    - 1942 (Box 6)
      - General (Folder 6: 1)
      - Masaryk, Jan (Folder 6: 2)
      - Munich agreement, Annulment of (Folder 6: 3)
      - Profiles of government members according to Polish intelligence (Folder 6: 4)
      - Ripka, Hubert
        - General (Folder 6: 5)
        - Speeches (Folder 6: 6)
    - 1943
      - General
        - January-June (Folder 6: 7)
        - July-December (Folder 6: 8)
      - Ripka, Hubert (Folder 6: 9)
    - 1944
      - General
        - General (Folder 6: 10)
        - January-April (Folder 6: 11)
        - May-August (Folder 6: 12)
        - September-December (Folder 6: 13)
      - Slovakia (Folder 6: 14)
    - 1945
      - General
        - General (Folder 6: 15)
        - Ministerstwo Obrony Narodowej (Ministry of National Defense). Intelligence reports (Folder 6: 16)
      - Czech National Union in London (Folder 6: 17)
  - C/State Council
    - 1941 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - 1942 (Folder 7: 2)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 7: 3)
      - "Zpravy Statni Rady" (Folder 7: 4)
    - 1944 (Folder 7: 5)
    - 1945. (Folder 7: 6)
      Includes documents on army
  - D/Foreign representations and diplomatic corps
    - 1941
      - General
        - General (Folder 7: 7)
        - Political and economic reports (Folder 7: 8)
      - Diplomatic corps
        - Bulletin (Folder 7: 9)
        - List (Folder 7: 10)
    - 1942
      - Bulletin (Folder 7: 11)
      - List (Folder 7: 12)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 7: 13)
      - Lists (Folder 7: 14)
    - 1944 (Folder 7: 15)
  - E/Occupied Czechoslovakia
    - 1942
      - General - Czechoslovak Newsletter (Folder 7: 16)
      - German atrocities (Folder 7: 17)
      - Slovakia (Folder 7: 18)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 7: 19)
      - Czechoslovak Newsletter (Folder 7: 20)
      - Prague press (Folder 7: 21)
    - 1944 (Folder 7: 22)
    - 1945 (Folder 7: 23)
  - F/Organizations, opposition groups (Box 8)
    - 1941 (Folder 8: 1)
    - 1942
      - General (Folder 8: 2)
      - Masaryk - Gaster Fund of the Federation of Czechoslovak Jews (Folder 8: 3)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 8: 4)
      - Osusky, Stefan (Folder 8: 5)
    - 1944
      - General (Folder 8: 6)
      - Czech National Union in London (Folder 8: 7)
      - Czechoslovak Relief Action (Folder 8: 8)
  - G/Biographies - Slovaks. (Folder 8: 9)
    Includes Slovaks in the United States
- SERIES NO. VII. POLAND. GOVERNMENT AND ADMINISTRATION
  - B/Government
    - 1941 (Folder 8: 10)
    - 1942
      - General (Folder 8: 11)
      - Zbirka Posudku Pravni Rady Statniho Zrizeni Ceskoslovenskeho (Folder 8: 12)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 8: 13)
      - Ministerstwo Pracy i Opieki Spolecznej Biuletyn (Folder 8: 14)
    - 1944
      - Ministries
        - Ministerstwo Obrony Narodowej (Ministry of National Defense) (Folder 8: 15)
        - Ministerstwo Pracy i Opieki Spolecznej (Ministry of Labor and Social Welfare) (Folder 8: 16)
        - Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Ministry of Foreign Affairs) (Folder 8: 17)
      - Moscow-backed government (Folder 8: 18)
  - C/State Council
    - 1942 (Folder 8: 19)
    - 1943. (Folder 8: 20)
      Includes documents on German political émigrés
  - D/Diplomatic corps
    - 1941 - Polish diplomatic corps in Great Britain and the world (Folder 8: 21)
    - 1943 (Folder 8: 22)
  - E/Occupied Poland
    - 1941 (Folder 8: 23)
    - 1942 (Folder 8: 24)
    - 1943
      - Persecution of Jews (Folder 8: 25)
      - Polish-Ukrainian relations (Folder 8: 26)
    - 1944
      - Concentration camps protest (Folder 8: 27)
      - Moscow backed Poles (Folder 8: 28)
    - 1945 - Lublin government (Folder 8: 29)
  - F/Polish organizations abroad (Box 9)
    - 1941. (Folder 9: 1)
      Includes documents on Cieszyn Poles
    - 1942 (Folder 9: 2)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 9: 3)
      - Commonwealth of Central Europe (Folder 9: 4)
    - 1945 - Recognition of Lublin government (Folder 9: 5)
- SERIES NO. VIII. POLITICAL CONDITIONS
  - A/Reports
    - 1941 (Folder 9: 6)
    - 1942 (Folder 9: 7)
    - 1944 (Folder 9: 8)
  - B/Political guidelines
    - 1941 (Folder 9: 9)
    - 1942 (Folder 9: 10)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 9: 11)
      - Poland's eastern borders (Folder 9: 12)
      - Transfer of Germans from Poland (Folder 9: 13)
    - 1944 (Folder 9: 14)
  - C/Inter-governmental committees, international conditions
    - 1941 (Folder 9: 15)
    - 1943
      - Interallied Committee on Armistice (Folder 9: 16)
      - War crimes and armistice (Folder 9: 17)
  - D/Exchange of political intelligence data (Box 10)
    - 1941
      - January-June (Folder 10: 1)
      - July-December (Folder 10: 2)
    - 1942 (Folder 10: 3)
    - 1943 (Folder 10: 4)
  - F/International organizations, League of Nations
    - 1942 - Federation of Western Slavs (Folder 10: 5)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 6)
- SERIES NO. IX. ECONOMIC ISSUES
  - A/Poland
    - 1941 (Folder 10: 7)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 8)
  - B/Czechoslovakia
    - 1941 (Folder 10: 9)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 10)
    - 1945 (Folder 10: 11)
  - C/General reports
    - 1942 (Folder 10: 12)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 13)
  - D/Slask Cieszynski (Teschen Silesia)
    - 1918 - Border negotiations (Folder 10: 14)
    - 1938 (Folder 10: 15)
    - 1942
      - General (Folder 10: 16)
      - Slask Cieszynski (Folder 10: 17)
      - Zaglebie Ostrawsko-Kawinskie (Folder 10: 18)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 10: 19)
      - Slask Cieszynski (Folder 10: 20)
- SERIES NO. X. ADMINISTRATIVE OPERATIONS
  - A/Addresses and financial matters
    - 1941 (Folder 10: 21)
    - 1942 (Folder 10: 22)
    - 1943
      - General (Folder 10: 23)
      - Business cards (Folder 10: 24)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 25)
    - 1945 (Folder 10: 26)
  - B/Diplomatic protocol
    - 1941 (Folder 11: 1)
    - 1942 (Folder 11: 2)
    - 1943 (Folder 11: 3)
    - 1944 (Folder 11: 4)
    - 1945 (Folder 11: 5)
  - C/Medals and awards (mail and rent)
    - 1941-1943 (Folder 11: 6)
    - 1944 (Folder 11: 7)
  - D/Personal files (state employees)
    - 1940-1943 (Folder 11: 8)
    - 1945 (Folder 11: 9)
  - E/Budget
    - 1942 (Folder 11: 10)
    - 1943 (Folder 11: 11)
  - F/Library and publications
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 11: 13)
    - 1944 (Folder 11: 13)
    - 1945 (Folder 11: 14)
- SERIES NO. XI. VARIA
  - A/Mailing procedures
    - 1941 (Folder 11: 15)
    - 1942 (Folder 11: 16)
    - 1943 (Folder 11: 17)
  - B/Treatment of correspondence, 1941-1943 (Folder 11: 18)
  - C/Meetings, congresses, social organizations, courses, 1941-1943 (Folder 11: 19)
- SERIES NO. XII. CONSULAR MATTERS (Box 12)
  - A/Interventions
    - 1941 (Folder 12: 1)
    - 1942 (Folder 12: 2)
  - B/Legal issues, 1941-1943 (Folder 12: 3)
  - C/Circulars
    - 1941 (Folder 12: 4)
    - 1942 (Folder 12: 5)
    - 1943 (Folder 12: 6)
- SERIES NO. XIII. PRESS AND PUBLICATIONS
  - A/Polish
    - a/Press interviews, 1941 (Folder 12: 7)
    - b/Polish press on Czechoslovakia
      - 1941
        - Clippings (Folder 12: 8)
        - Reports (Folder 12: 9)
      - 1942
        - General (Folder 12: 10)
        - Reports (Folder 12: 11)
      - 1943
        - General (Folder 12: 12)
        - Correspondence (Folder 12: 13)
    - c/Propaganda publications
      - 1941 (Folder 12: 14)
      - 1943 (Folder 12: 15)
  - B/Czechoslovak
    - a/Press reports
      - 1941
        - January-June (Folder 12: 16)
        - July-December (Folder 12: 17)
      - 1942
        - General
          - January-June (Folder 12: 18)
          - July-December (Folder 12: 19)
        - Ministerstwo Informacji i Dokumentacji (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - 1943
        - General (Folder 13: 2)
        - Ministerstwo Informacji i Dokumentacji (Folder 13: 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 13: 4)
    - b/Czechoslovak press on Poland
      - 1941 (Folder 13: 5)
      - 1942 (Folder 13: 6)
      - 1943 (Folder 13: 7)
    - c/Publications
      - 1941
        - General (Folder 13: 8)
        - List of Czech publications in Great Britain (Folder 13: 9)
      - 1943
        - General (Folder 13: 10)
        - Centropa News Service (Folder 13: 11)
      - 1944 - Centropa News Service (Folder 13: 12)
    - d/Uredni Vestnik Ceskoslovensky
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 13: 13)
      - 1943 (Folder 13: 14)
  - C/Other
    - a/British press on Czechoslovakia
      - 1941 (Folder 13: 15)
      - 1942 (Folder 13: 16)
      - 1943 (Folder 13: 17)
      - 1944 (Folder 13: 18)
    - b/German press on Czechoslovakia (Box 14)
      - 1941 (Folder 14: 1)
      - 1942 (Folder 14: 2)
      - 1943 (Folder 14: 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 14: 4)
    - c/Publications on federation
      - 1941 (Folder 14: 5)
      - 1942 (Folder 14: 6)
      - 1943
        - General (Folder 14: 7)